If this story ain't true... it shoulda been!
The Life and Times of Judge Roy Bean is a western,
comedy film directed by John Huston.
Outlaw and self-appointed lawmaker Judge Roy Bean rules over an empty stretch of the West that gradually grows, under his iron
fist, into a thriving town, while dispensing his his own quirky brand of frontier justice upon strangers passing by.
Judge Roy Bean, played by Paul Newman.
Maria Elena, played by Victoria Principal.
Tector Crites, played by Ned Beatty.
Nick the Grub, played by Matt Clark.
Frank Gass, played by Roddy McDowall.
Rose Bean, played by Jacqueline Bisset.
The Life and Times of Judge Roy Bean is a 1972 American Western comedy-drama film
written by John Milius, directed by John Huston, and starring Paul Newman.
It is loosely based on the life of American saloon-keeper and
Justice of the Peace in Val Verde County, Texas Roy Bean.
The film explores themes of judge, outlaw, lawyer.
The tone is lighthearted.